THOMAS MYRDEN

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT

myrden.com

**** 902 210 2500

f tmyrden

y tmyrden

in tmyrden

O tmyrden

SKILLS

CLIENT SIDE DEVELOPMENT

JavaScript

HTML

CSS

Cross-Browser Development

SERVER SIDE DEVELOPMENT

Node.js

SQL

Java

PHP

OPERATIONS TOOLING

Chef

Nagios

Vagrant

MOBILE DEVELOPMENT

iOS App Development

Moderate Experience with Android

OTHER

Realtime Programming

Test Driven Development

Software Documentation

Git

Public Speaking

SUMMARY

I am a well rounded developer with experience in front-end, back-end, mobile and operations. Most recently I've been working as an iOS developer to build Salesforce SOS. I bring an attention to detail and passion for good user experience to work every day.

EDUCATION

The University of Western Ontario

Bachelor of Science Double Major: Computer Science & Medical Sciences 2012 Coursework: Applied Logic, Computer Law, Business for Sciences, Data Structures & Algorithms, Computer Architecture, Databases, Operating Systems, Artificial Intelligence, Medical Imaging.

EMPLOYMENT

salesforce.com

Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada

Developer, SOS & Golnstant

Jun 2013 to Current

Developing an in-app support SDK for iOS. Users are connected to an agent who is able to see the user's screen and guide them through use of the iOS app.

- Created multiple iterations of the demo app to showcase SOS to prospective customers.
- Develop & architect features of the iOS framework.
- Responsible for developer tooling, including automated build process and continuous integration.

Developed a realtime API for data storage and synchronization that implemented a JSON key/value store paired with a pub-sub messaging interface.

- Designed and implemented the REST API to allow server interactions with the data. Thorough test driven development was used to ensure robust security.
- Worked in a DevOps role and was responsible for overnight code deployment, on-call
 crisis response, server automation via Chef, and management of our AWS stack.
- Presented at an MLH hackathon, promoting the Golnstant product and giving a talk on the transition from school to full-time employment.
- Created JavaScript "widgets" to allow for drop-in implementation of many common realtime use cases. Examples include a chat widget and a basic cobrowse widget.

Lixar IT

Junior Developer

Oct 2012 to May 2013

Worked on a team that developed a web version of a PC game called "APBA" - a fantasy baseball simulator.

- Independently developed the live draft room, utilizing JavaScript to perform long polling to our REST API.
- Solely responsible for homepage redesign and the site's CSS work.
- Created much of the PHP to serve player data from the REST API.

The Waegwoltic Club

Assistant Head Sailing Instructor

Mar 2011 to Sep 2012

Sailing Coach

May 2007 to Sep 2012

The Waegwoltic Club has the largest learn to sail program in Atlantic Canada, with more than 200 sailors each summer.

- Coached competitive racing while holding the position of Assistant Head Instructor, involving the on-water management of classes further to my own.
- Regularly performed fiberglass, sail, and outboard motor repairs.